IVAN FELIPE ESCOBAR

Atlanta, GA, 30309 I (770) 880-4516 I lvnEscbr1989@Gmail.com
GitHub: https://www.github.com/IvanFelipeEscobar
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivan-felipe-escobar

Full Stack Web Developer with a Certificate in Web Development from the Georgia Institute if Technology. Strong creative problem-solving skills developed over 15 years in the automotive industry, as well as competent communication skills gained from customer interaction.

Skills Summary

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, Structured Query Language (SQL), NoSQL, GitHub, Heroku, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, RESTful API, GraphQL.

Strong creative problem-solving skills, extensive customer service experience, and an eagerness to continue to learn new technologies to further my understanding.

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – Georgia Institute of Technology – 2023

G.E.D - 2009

Projects

TomatoDuck I https://github.com/indwomt/tomatoduck I https://tomatoduck.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full Stack Web Application heavily inspired by Promofocus.io
- Role: Co-author with Lauren Bentley (https://github.com/indwomt)
- Tools: React, Express Server, RESTful API, MongoDB, Bootstrap, JSON Web Tokens, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Tech Blog I https://github.com/lvanFelipeEscobar/Tech-Blog I https://technology-blog-spot.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Generic blog site with user authentication and server-side rendering
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Express, Handlebars, JS, MySQL, Bootstrap, HTML5, JavaScript

Meme-Libl https://github.com/lvanFelipeEscobar/MemeLib https://ivanfelipeescobar.github.io/MemeLib/

- Summary: Meme Library fetches memes from third party API to allow user to populate library
- Role: Principal author with help from Tyler Johnson (https://github.com/tylerjohnsonhockey) and Jordan Grainger (https://github.com/jomanG32)
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Foundation Framework, JavaScript

Experience

Maximotor 2021-Present

Shop Manager / Lead Technician

Marietta, GA

- Communicate with customer, technician, and vendors to maintain a smooth and timely workflow. Consistently meeting projected deadlines.
- Use QuickBooks to maintain inventory, billing/invoicing, payroll, tax filing and reporting among many other administrative duties.
- Occasional automotive repair and maintenance.

Village Garage & Custom

2018-2020

Automotive Technician

Atlanta, GA

- Performed desired automotive repairs and maintenance according to customer needs.
- On older vehicles with limited parts availability had to engineer long term solutions to maintain vehicles safe to drive
- Helped design, source and implement custom modifications to customer vehicles.

K&M Foreign & Domestic Auto Repair

2016-2018

Automotive Technician

Atlanta, GA

• Completed repairs and maintenance services specified by work order.